{
    "id": "4a5d0fe9ea024e709176b125f2fe501f",
    "title": "Tenses Gap Filling Exercise",
    "questions": [
        {
            "question": "………………………. you know where she lives?",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "Do",
                "Does",
                "Has"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………. park in front of the shop.",
            "description": "The subject of an imperative sentence is always you. Hence, we use do.",
            "answers": [
                "Don't",
                "Doesn't",
                "Either could be used here"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "………………………… your shoes off before entering the temple.",
            "description": "We use a plural verb in imperative sentences. ",
            "answers": [
                "Take",
                "Takes",
                "Taking"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "The world will run out of oil unless it ……………………………………. conservation.",
            "description": "In the first conditional, use a simple present tense in the subordinate clause and will + first form of the verb in the main clause. ",
            "answers": [
                "will practice",
                "practiced",
                "practices"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "The police are looking for a woman who ……………………………. her children.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "deserted",
                "deserts",
                "deserting"
            ],
            "correct": 0
        },
        {
            "question": "She …………………………… on a new project at the moment.",
            "description": "The present continuous is used to talk about actions or situations that are going on around now. ",
            "answers": [
                "works",
                "has worked",
                "is working"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "She ……………………………… to him for twenty years.",
            "description": "The present perfect is commonly used with the time expressions for and since to show duration. ",
            "answers": [
                "is married",
                "is marrying",
                "has been married"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "My cat ……………………………. for over three weeks now.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "is missing",
                "missed",
                "has missed",
                "has been missing"
            ],
            "correct": 3
        },
        {
            "question": "If you had been careful, you ……………………………….. yourself.",
            "description": "In third conditional, use a past perfect tense in the if clause and would have + past participle in the main clause.",
            "answers": [
                "will not injure",
                "would not injure",
                "would not have injured"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "As soon as she ……………………………. I told her the news.",
            "description": "When the verb in the main clause is in the past tense, use a past tense in the subordinate clause as well. ",
            "answers": [
                "arrives",
                "arrived",
                "arrive"
            ],
            "correct": 1
        },
        {
            "question": "The old woman …………………………… alone.",
            "description": "The simple present is used to talk about permanent situations. ",
            "answers": [
                "has lived",
                "live",
                "lives"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        },
        {
            "question": "I asked him if he …………………………….. my cat.",
            "description": "",
            "answers": [
                "saw",
                "has seen",
                "had seen"
            ],
            "correct": 2
        }
    ]
}